Guide to the Monroe Wheeler Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1921-88, n.d.; Series II; 3.15; (8 boxes)
  - LECTURES & SPEECHES
    - Presentation to René d'Harnoncourt, notecards, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 522)
    - Remarks at Edward Steichen memorial service at MOMA, background information, 1959-73 (Box 22, Folder 523)
    - Remarks at Edward Steichen memorial service at MOMA, drafts, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 524)
    - "Remarks for Santiago", draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 525)
    - [Report to the Grolier Club?], draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 526)
    - [re: David Smith exhibition in Nürenberg], drafts, typescript, corrected, 1967 Jan (Box 22, Folder 527)
      [in English and German; includes page of radio interview transcript in German]
    - "To the Members of the American Institute of Graphic Arts", draft, typescript, carbon, 1960 Oct 12 (Box 22, Folder 528)
    - Tribute to Lincoln Kirstein, draft fragment, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1973 Nov 13 (Box 22, Folder 529)
    - Untitled, re: art, notecards, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 530-533)
    - Untitled, re: art, notecards, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 534-538)
    - Untitled, re: art and the universe, draft pages, typescript, corrected, ca. 1959 (Box 23, Folder 539)
    - Untitled, re: Bonnard, notecards, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 540)
    - Untitled, "For possible future use", notecards, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 541)
    - Untitled, re: Matisse. notecards, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 542)
    - Untitled, re: History of MOMA, notecards, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 543)
    - Untitled, re: MOMA, notecards, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 544-545)
    - Untitled, re: MW's career at MOMA, notecards, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 546)
    - Untitled, re: Rouault, notecards, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 547)
    - Untitled, re: Edwards Steichen, notecards, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 548)
    - Untitled, re: MW's life, notecards, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 549)
    - Untitled, notecards with questions from the audience, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 550)
    - Notebook for various lectures, ca. 1941-72 (Box 23, Folder 551)
    - Notebook for various lectures, ca. 1957-82 (Box 24, Folder 552)
      includes: "Character and Temperament in Modern Art" and "The Phenomenal Popularity of Modern Art"
    - Background clippings for unspecified lectures, ca. 1956-63 (Box 24, Folder 553)
    - Notes for unspecified lectures, ca. 1940-70 (Box 24, Folder 554)
    - Notices and reviews for lectures by MW, 1964, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 555)
  - WRITINGS ABOUT MW
    - "Authenticating my Portrait by Modigliani" by Konrad Bercovici, printed version, The Courier [Syracuse University], [1965] (Box 25, Folder 556)
      includes copy of The Courier, 1964 Mar, with article re: Bercovici
    - "Entries from an Early Diary" by Lincoln Kirstein, printed version, Dance Perspectives 54, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 557)
    - "Interview: Mr. Monroe Wheeler" by "P. S.", transcript, 1955 Apr (Box 25, Folder 558)
    - "The Persuader", printed version, Connoisseur, 1983 Oct (Box 25, Folder 559-560)
      includes tearsheets of illustrations
    - "Profile: Monroe Wheeler", printed version, Apollo, 1964 Jun (Box 25, Folder 561)
      includes notes on MW by GW sent to Mario Amaya [possibly the author of the unsigned profile]
    - "Profile: Monroe Wheeler", offprint from Apollo, 1964 Jun (Box 25, Folder 562)
    - "Two Afternoons with Monroe" [profile for MOMA newsletter] by Wendy Wilder Larsen, typescript, corrected, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 563)
    - "La Visita de un Hombre con Suerte", printed version, Cosas, 1984 Jan 12 (Box 25, Folder 564)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Amaya, Mario
      - "Aesthetic Butterfly", proof, 1960 Oct (Box 26, Folder 565)
      - "The Now of Yesterday:, galley proof, 1963 Mar (Box 26, Folder 566)
      - "The Painter who Inspired Hollywood", printed version, The Sunday Times Magazine, 1968 Feb 18
    - Auden, W. H.
      - "Lullaby", holograph copy by Jerry Rosco, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 567)
    - Benitez, Jaime
      - "The United States, Cuba, and Latin America: Preface", typescript mimeograph (Box 26, Folder 568)
    - Borges, Jorge Luis
      - "Borges and I" [English translation by Anthony Berrigan], typescript copy (Box 26, Folder 569)
    - Colum, Padraic
      - "Sleep and a Laburnum Tree", typescript, corrected, 1965 Aug (Box 26, Folder 570)
    - Dinesen, Isak
      - "On Mottoes of My Life", draft, typescript, 1959 Mar (Box 26, Folder 571)
    - Frash, Robert
      - Introduction to Charlton film re: Loren MacIver, transcript, typescript, corrected, photocopy, 1972 May 10 (Box 26, Folder 572)
    - Green, Julien
      - "Julien Green's Journal Volume VI, Paris 1955" [section re: GW], typescript carbon copy, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 573)
    - Heine, Heinrich
      - [Anecdotes], translated by Mina Curtiss, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 574)
    - Hellman, [Lillian?]
      - "Sitwell Rehearses" [article for The New Yorker ], galley proof, corrected, 1950 Nov (Box 26, Folder 575)
    - Henderson, Alva
      - List of works with reviews, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 576)
    - Hope-Gill, Cecil
      - "I Remember it Well", title page draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 577)
    - Huxley, Aldous
      - "Art and the Obvious", mimeograph copy (Box 26, Folder 578)
    - Johnson, S. F.
      - "'Critics and Criticism': A Discussion, The Chicago Manifesto", offprint, 1953 Dec (Box 26, Folder 579)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln
      - "Phenomena: A Topical Dialogue", typescript carbon, 1946 Nov 20 (Box 26, Folder 580)
    - Lebeck, Michael
      - "Album: Poems", draft, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 581)
    - Lee, Arthur
      - "Sculpture", typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 582)
    - McGuinn, Brad
      - Essay on Greece, draft pages, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 583)
    - Moore, T. Sturge
      - "To Giacomo Leopardi", holograph, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 584)
    - Pagano, Mark
      - "The Toe of Beauty", draft, typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 585)
      - "Who was that Rude Young Man?", draft, typescript, corrected, photocopy (Box 26, Folder 586)
    - Phelps, Robert
      - Inscription to MW in copy on Professional Secrets, holograph, photocopy, 1970 Jul 28 (Box 26, Folder 587)
    - Poe, Edgar Allan
      - "The Philosophy of Furniture", typescript and carbon copies (Box 26, Folder 588)
    - Pohorilenko, Anatole
      - "Dr. Wauchope: A Personal Account", draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1978 Feb 2 (Box 26, Folder 589)
      - "Dr. Wauchope: A Personal Account", offprint, 1978 Feb 2 (Box 26, Folder 590)
      - "Olmec 'Baby-Face' Representation: A Study in Pre-Columbian Paleopathology", draft, typescript, photocopy, 1980 May (Box 26, Folder 591)
    - Renard, Jules
      - "Poil de Carotte" [translated by Ralph Manheim], galley proof [incomplete], n.d. (Box 26, Folder 592)
    - Rosten, Leo
      - "The Creative Idea", typescript carbon copy, 1963 May (Box 26, Folder 593)
    - Rothschild, Philippe de
      - Untitled Speech, transcript, typescript, corrected, photocopy, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 594)
    - Severini, Gino
      - "La Morale de l'Art", holograph with typescript and carbon transcriptions (Box 26, Folder 595)
    - Sihare, Laxmi
      - "Oriental Influences on the Four Pioneers of Non-Representational Painting", dissertation outline, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 596)
    - Sitwell, Edith
      - "Old Sir Faulk", typescript copy, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 597)
    - Sitwell, Sacheverell
      - "Je suis Brésilien, j'ai de l'or", photocopy of chapter from Baroque and Rococo, printed version, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 598)
    - Strykalski, Joshua
      - "Taglione's Jewel Casket", draft, holograph, photocopy, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 599)
    - Szold Fritz, Bernardine
      - Anecdote re: death of Isadora Duncan, for The New Yorker, galley proof, corrected, 1969 Jun 25 (Box 26, Folder 600)
    - Spark, Muriel
      - "The Desegregation of Art", transcript of speech, typescript, photocopy, 1970 May 26 (Box 26, Folder 601)
    - Spears, Woodridge
      - "Toward 'In the Great Steep's Garden' and Chicago", draft, typescript, photocopy, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 602)
    - Stevenson, John
      - Journal of a visit to France, draft, computer printout, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 603)
    - Wescott, Barbara
      - Member letter for the Association for the Arts, draft, typescript carbon, 1971 Jan 10 (Box 26, Folder 604)
    - Wojtasik, Theodore, A. Jr.
      - "Comments on Keeping a Journal", draft, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 605)
    - Unidentified
      - Page re: bullfight, page proof, 1931 Apr 23 (Box 26, Folder 606)
      - Group of sexual narratives, typescript carbon, 1944 May 2 (Box 26, Folder 607)
      - re: Kay Boyle and Harold Stearns, draft fragment, typescript, photocopy (Box 26, Folder 608)
      - "Portrait of Hope", typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 609)
      - Story of Albert and Jacques [in French], draft, typescript carbon (Box 26, Folder 610)
        [page 1 lacking]
      - "Stories of Observation out of Several Books", typescript copy, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 611)
- Personal Papers, 1890-1995; Series III; 46; (112 boxes)
  Series III, Personal Papers, consists of twelve subseries, which are arranged chronologically and alphabetically.
  - DIARIES
    - Diary, 1928-32 (Box 27, Folder 612)
    - Diary, 1933-37 (Box 27, Folder 613)
    - Diary, 1935 (Box 27, Folder 614)
    - Diary, 1936 (Box 27, Folder 615)
    - Diary, 1936-37 (Box 28, Folder 616)
    - Diary, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 617)
    - Diary, 1938-42 (Box 28, Folder 618)
    - Diary, 1943-47 (Box 28, Folder 619)
    - Diary, 1946-59 (Box 29, Folder 620)
    - Diary, 1948-52 (Box 29, Folder 621)
    - Diary, 1949 (Box 29, Folder 622)
    - Diary, 1953-57 (Box 29, Folder 623)
    - Diary, 1958-62 (Box 30, Folder 624)
    - Diary, 1960-80s (Box 30, Folder 625)
    - Diary, 1963-67 (Box 30, Folder 626)
    - Diary, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 627)
    - Diary, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 628)
    - Diary, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 629)
  - DATEBOOKS
    - Datebook: "Northwestern Handbook", 1918-19 (Box 32, Folder 630)
    - Datebook, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 631)
    - Datebook, 1934 (Box 32, Folder 632)
    - Datebook, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 633)
    - Datebook, 1936 (Box 32, Folder 634)
    - Datebook, 1937 (Box 32, Folder 635)
    - Datebook, 1937 (Box 32, Folder 636)
    - Datebook, 1938 (Box 32, Folder 637)
    - Datebook, 1939 (Box 32, Folder 638)
    - Datebook, 1940 (Box 32, Folder 639)
    - Datebook, 1941 (Box 33, Folder 640)
    - Datebook, 1941 (Box 33, Folder 641)
    - Datebook, 1942 (Box 33, Folder 642)
    - Datebook, 1943 (Box 33, Folder 643)
    - Datebook, 1943 (Box 33, Folder 644)
    - Datebook, 1944 (Box 33, Folder 645)
    - Datebook, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 646)
    - Datebook, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 647)
    - Datebook, 1945 (Box 34, Folder 648)
    - Datebook, 1945 (Box 34, Folder 649)
    - Datebook, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 650)
    - Datebook, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 651)
    - Datebook, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 652)
    - Datebook, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 653)
    - Datebook, 1948 (Box 35, Folder 654)
    - Datebook, 1948 (Box 35, Folder 655)
    - Datebook, 1949 (Box 35, Folder 656)
    - Datebook, 1949 (Box 35, Folder 657)
    - Datebook, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 658)
    - Datebook, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 659)
    - Datebook, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 660)
    - Datebook, 1951 (Box 36, Folder 661)
    - Datebook, 1952 (Box 36, Folder 662)
    - Datebook, 1953 (Box 36, Folder 663)
    - Datebook, 1953 (Box 36, Folder 664)
    - Datebook, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 665)
    - Datebook, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 666)
    - Datebook, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 667)
    - Datebook, 1956 (Box 36, Folder 668)
    - Datebook, 1956 (Box 37, Folder 669)
    - Datebook, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 670)
    - Datebook, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 671)
    - Datebook, 1958 (Box 37, Folder 672)
    - Datebook, 1958 (Box 37, Folder 673)
    - Datebook, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 674)
    - Datebook, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 675)
    - Datebook, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 676)
    - Datebook, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 677)
    - Datebook, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 678)
    - Datebook, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 679)
    - Datebook, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 680)
    - Datebook, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 681)
    - Datebook, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 682)
    - Datebook, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 683)
    - Datebook, 1963 (Box 39, Folder 684)
    - Datebook, 1963 (Box 39, Folder 685)
    - Datebook, 1963 (Box 39, Folder 686)
    - Datebook, 1963 (Box 39, Folder 687)
    - Datebook, 1964 (Box 39, Folder 688)
    - Datebook, 1964 (Box 39, Folder 689)
    - Datebook, 1965 (Box 40, Folder 690)
    - Datebook, 1965 (Box 40, Folder 691)
    - Datebook, 1966 (Box 40, Folder 692)
    - Datebook, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 693)
    - Datebook, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 694)
    - Datebook, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 695)
    - Datebook, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 696)
    - Datebook, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 697)
    - Datebook pages, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 698)
    - Datebook, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 699)
    - Datebook, 1970 (Box 41, Folder 700)
    - Datebook, 1970 (Box 41, Folder 701)
    - Datebook, 1970 (Box 41, Folder 702)
    - Datebook, 1970 (Box 41, Folder 703)
    - Datebook, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 704)
    - Datebook, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 705)
    - Datebook, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 706)
    - Datebook, 1973 (Box 41, Folder 707)
    - Datebook, 1973 (Box 41, Folder 708)
    - Datebook, 1974 (Box 42, Folder 709)
    - Datebook, 1974 (Box 42, Folder 710)
    - Datebook, 1975 (Box 42, Folder 711)
    - Datebook, 1975 (Box 42, Folder 712)
    - Datebook, 1975 (Box 42, Folder 713)
    - Datebook, 1976 (Box 42, Folder 714)
    - Datebook, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 715)
    - Datebook, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 716)
    - Datebook, 1978 (Box 42, Folder 717)
    - Datebook, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 718)
    - Datebook, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 719)
    - Datebook, 1980 (Box 42, Folder 720)
    - Datebook, 1980 (Box 42, Folder 721)
    - Datebook, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 722)
    - Datebook, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 723)
    - Datebook, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 724)
    - Datebook, 1983 (Box 43, Folder 725)
    - Datebook, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 726)
    - Datebook, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 727)
    - Datebook, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 728)
    - Datebook, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 729)
    - Datebook, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 730)
    - Datebook, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 731)
    - Datebook, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 732)
    - Datebook, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 733)
    - Datebook, 1987 (Box 44, Folder 734)
    - Datebook, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 735)
  - ADDRESSES
    - Address book: "Foreign", n.d. (Box 45, Folder 736)
    - Address book: "MW's confidential list of guests", n.d. (Box 45, Folder 737)
    - Address book: "U.S.", n.d. (Box 45, Folder 738)
    - Address book, ca. 1930 (Box 45, Folder 739)
    - Address book, 1959 (Box 45, Folder 740)
    - Address book, 1959 (Box 45, Folder 741)
    - Address book, ca. 1980s (Box 45, Folder 742)
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 743)
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 744)
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 745)
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 746)
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 747)
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 748)
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 749)
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 750)
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 751)
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 752)
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 753)
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 754)
    - Address cards, n.d. (Box 48)
    - Address cards, n.d. (Box 49)
  - NOTEBOOKS
    - "A", ca. 1958 (Box 50, Folder 755)
    - "A, misc. notes, quotes", ca. 1967-68 (Box 50, Folder 756)
    - "Art", ca. 1951-86 (Box 51, Folder 757)
    - "Art: Notes & Projects", ca. 1943-73 (Box 51, Folder 758)
    - "Daily Agenda" (Box 52, Folder 759)
    - "Foster / Mortimer, G. Wescott, Maugham / Sitwell", ca. 1948-70 (Box 52, Folder 760)
    - "late notes", n.d. (Box 52, Folder 761)
    - "Moore / Porter", ca. 1963-72 (Box 53, Folder 762)
    - "MW's acetate album", ca. 1980-83 (Box 53, Folder 763)
    - "MW B, misc. notes, quotes", ca. 1967-68 (Box 54, Folder 764)
    - "MW's Diary Material, ca. 1977" (Box 54, Folder 765)
    - "MW Varia", ca. 1964-72 (Box 55, Folder 766)
    - "Notes", ca. 1967-85 (Box 55, Folder 767)
    - "Notes AA", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 768)
    - "Notes BB", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 769)
    - "Notes CC", n.d. (Box 57, Folder 770)
    - "Place/Food", n.d. (Box 57, Folder 771)
    - Quotations 1-208, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 772)
    - Quotations 1-208, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 773)
    - Quotations 210-385, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 774)
    - Quotations 210-385, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 775)
    - Quotations, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 776)
    - Quotations, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 777)
    - Quotations, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 778)
    - "To Do", ca. 1984 (Box 61, Folder 779)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1941-86 (Box 61, Folder 780)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1943-65 (Box 61, Folder 781)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1950-86 (Box 62, Folder 782)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1952-73 (Box 62, Folder 783)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1952-83 (Box 63, Folder 784)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1955-80 (Box 63, Folder 785)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1957-69
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1960-77 (Box 64, Folder 786)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1961-68 (Box 64, Folder 787)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1961-69 (Box 64, Folder 788)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1964-70 (Box 65, Folder 789)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1965-68 (Box 65, Folder 790)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1968-73 (Box 66, Folder 791)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1971 (Box 66, Folder 792)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1972-79 (Box 67, Folder 793)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1974 (Box 67, Folder 794)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1975 (Box 67, Folder 795)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1975-83 (Box 68, Folder 796)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1977 (Box 68, Folder 797)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1978-80 (Box 68, Folder 798)
    - Untitled notebook, ca. 1984 (Box 69, Folder 799)
    - Untitled notebook, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 800)
    - Untitled notebook, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 801)
    - Untitled notebook, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 802)
    - Untitled notebook, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 803)
    - Untitled notebook, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 804)
    - Untitled notebook, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 805)
    - Untitled notebook, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 806)
    - Loose notebook material, ca. 1953-71 (Box 71, Folder 807)
  - JOURNALS
    - Journal (binder notebook), ca. 1964-70 (Box 72, Folder 808)
    - Journal (binder notebook), ca. 1972-73 (Box 72, Folder 809)
    - Journal pages: "Selections from a 1937-38 journal, carbon copies", ca. 1937-38 (Box 72, Folder 810)
    - Journal pages, 1948-87 (Box 72, Folder 811-812)
    - Journal notes, 1942, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 813)
    - Journal notes: "MW's notes on his visit to W. Somerset Maugham", 1952 Sep (Box 73, Folder 814)
    - Journal notes, 1952, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 815)
    - Journal notes, ca. 1953-71 (Box 73, Folder 816)
    - Journal notes: "Notes for journal and 1954 datepad (from 410 May 1955)", 1954-55 (Box 73, Folder 817)
    - Journal notes: "India, etc.", 1956 (Box 73, Folder 818)
    - Journal notes, 1956-83 (Box 73, Folder 819)
    - Journal notes: MW old scribbles and clippings, 20 years old", ca. 1957-58 (Box 73, Folder 820)
    - Journal notes, ca. 1961-62 (Box 73, Folder 821)
    - Journal notes, ca. 1964-69 (Box 73, Folder 822)
    - Journal notes, 1965 Oct 29 (Box 73, Folder 823)
    - Journal notes: "Europe December 1966 - January 1967", 1966-67 (Box 73, Folder 824)
    - Journal notes, ca. 1967 (Box 74, Folder 825)
    - Journal notes, 1967-70 (Box 74, Folder 826)
    - Journal notes: "October 1969" (Box 74, Folder 827)
    - Journal notes: "MW Travel notes", 1970 (Box 74, Folder 828)
    - Journal notes: "Dec. 23 '70 through Jan. 20, '71", 1970-71 (Box 74, Folder 829)
    - Journal notes, ca. 1971 (Box 74, Folder 830)
    - Journal notes, ca. 1974 (Box 74, Folder 831)
    - Journal notes: "Monroe Jottings", 1975 (Box 74, Folder 832)
    - Journal notes: "McCracken", 1977-85 (Box 74, Folder 833)
    - Journal notes, ca. 1980 (Box 74, Folder 834)
    - Journal notes: "Miscellany en route to Mouton", n.d. (Box 74, Folder 835)
    - Journal notes: "notes from Sarah's conversation", n.d. (Box 74, Folder 836)
    - Journal notes, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 837-839)
    - Loose notes, ca. 1949-86 (Box 74, Folder 840-842)
  - MEMOS & NOTEPADS
    - "1980" (Box 75, Folder 843)
    - "Agenda" (Box 75, Folder 844)
    - "Agenda" (Box 75, Folder 845)
    - "Agenda" (Box 75, Folder 846)
    - "Agenda" (Box 75, Folder 847)
    - "Agenda" (Box 75, Folder 848)
    - "Agenda" (Box 75, Folder 849)
    - "Agenda" (Box 75, Folder 850)
    - "April '73", 1973 (Box 75, Folder 851)
    - "Don't Forget", n.d. (Box 75, Folder 852)
    - "Europe 1977" (Box 75, Folder 853)
    - "Guatemala", n.d. (Box 75, Folder 854)
    - "Hampton", ca. 1980 (Box 75, Folder 855)
    - "Japan: August, September 1959" (Box 75, Folder 856)
    - "Old spiral copy-book jottings, N.Y. and Balt." (Box 75, Folder 857)
    - "Publications programs", n.d. (Box 76, Folder 858)
    - "Record", n.d. (Box 76, Folder 859)
    - "Riviera, Provence, Paris, Bogota"", 1979 May (Box 76, Folder 860)
    - "Spanish", n.d. (Box 76, Folder 861)
    - "Summer 1947" (Box 76, Folder 862)
    - "Telephone memo book", ca. 1985 (Box 76, Folder 863)
    - "Travel notes", ca. 1979 (Box 76, Folder 864)
    - "Woods Hole, August 1955, Notes - mainly Joyce", 1955 Aug (Box 76, Folder 865)
    - [Untitled, with note from GW on cover], n.d. (Box 76, Folder 866)
    - [Untitled, with photograph of MW on cover], n.d. (Box 76, Folder 867)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1948-63 (Box 76, Folder 868)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1956 (Box 76, Folder 869)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1957 (Box 77, Folder 870)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1962 (Box 77, Folder 871)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1965 (Box 77, Folder 872)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1966 (Box 77, Folder 873)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1967 (Box 77, Folder 874)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1967 (Box 77, Folder 875)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1967 (Box 77, Folder 876)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1968-71 (Box 77, Folder 877)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1970 (Box 77, Folder 878)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1970 (Box 77, Folder 879)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1970 (Box 78, Folder 880)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1970 (Box 78, Folder 881)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1970-71 (Box 78, Folder 882)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1971-74 (Box 78, Folder 883)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1972 (Box 78, Folder 884)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1972-73 (Box 78, Folder 885)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1973 (Box 78, Folder 886)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1973 (Box 78, Folder 887)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1974 (Box 78, Folder 888)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1974 (Box 78, Folder 889)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1975 (Box 79, Folder 890)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1975 (Box 79, Folder 891)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1976 (Box 79, Folder 892)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1976 (Box 79, Folder 893)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1977 (Box 79, Folder 894)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1977 (Box 79, Folder 895)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1978 (Box 79, Folder 896)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1979 (Box 79, Folder 897)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1980 (Box 79, Folder 898)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1981 (Box 79, Folder 899)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1982 (Box 79, Folder 900)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1983 (Box 79, Folder 901)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1985 (Box 80, Folder 902)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1985 (Box 80, Folder 903)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1985 (Box 80, Folder 904)
    - Memo / Notepad, ca. 1986 (Box 80, Folder 905)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 906-921)
    - Memos / Notepads, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 922-940)